STEPHANIE FAJARDO

Atlanta, GA 30309

Phone: 404-907-3848 | Email: stephfajardo@gatech.edu

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/stephfajardo | GitHub: github.com/stephtf | Portfolio: stephfajardo.com

Summary

My greatest strengths include my ability to problem solve, think critically, and maintain a high level of self-motivation. I offer a diverse skill set as someone who is trained in full-stack web development, UX design, qualitative research, and education. I excel at organizing and completing large projects, meeting tight deadlines, and working cooperatively with others in teams.

Technical Skills

Full-Stack: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Express, mySQL, MongoDB, Git UX Design: Figma, Adobe XD, wireframing and prototyping, usability studies, Final Cut Pro video editing

Projects

mentorMonkey

GitHub: https://github.com/caitlinw29/mentor-monkey | Heroku: https://secret-falls-29125.herokuapp.com

- mentorMonkey allows web developers to receive and give coding advice in real time
- created wireframes, constructed user interface, front-end javascript and handlebars
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, node.js, handlebars, mySQL, sequelize

Ultimate Urban Dictionary

GitHub: https://github.com/rwashi690/Urban_Dictionary_and_Memes | GitHub Pages: https://rwashi690.github.io/Urban_Dictionary_and_Memes | GitHub Pages:

- Ultimate Urban Dictionary allows users to keep up with the latest trends and slang
- developed front-end functionality in Javascript and constructed the user interface
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, jQuery, giphy API, Urban Dictionary API

historiography

GitHub: https://qithub.com/stephtf/historiography | Heroku: https://historiography.herokuapp.com

- historiography provides historians an easy way to organize historiographical information
- designed and developed the front and back end of the app from start to finish
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Node.js, handlebars, mySQL, Sequelize, Express

Experience

Postdoctoral Fellow, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

2021 – Present

- Develop research projects on US military families in the Philippines
- Create and teach an undergraduate course on US gender history

Postdoctoral Fellow, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

2020 - 2021

- Organized an international panel on anti-Asian violence for the Association of Asian American Studies annual conference
- Published three articles for SAGE Filipinx Studies Encyclopedia and a book

Research Supervisor, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

2019 - 2020

- Managed a large archival research and digitization project on the topic of US colonialism in the Philippines
- Facilitated research and digital skills workshops for undergraduate students

Research Fellow and Lecturer, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

2018 - 2019

- Conducted oral interviews in Tagalog for a Fulbright-sponsored project on gender and US military history in the Philippines
- Designed and taught History 195, an introductory historical writing course for college freshman

Education

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp Certificate Georgia Institute of Technology 03/09/2022

UX Google Certificate 11/19/2021

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) History/Women's Studies Graduate Certificate University of Michigan 08/21/2020

Masters in Teaching (MIT) Secondary Education University of Washington 12/16/2011

Bachelors of Arts (Triple Degree) History, Anthropology, and Spanish University of Washington 06/11/2010